chainstoreage.com 2018-06-24

# Privacy Policy | Chain Store Age

**INTRODUCTION**  
Lebhar-Friedman, Inc. (“LF”) is a media company providing readers who work in the retail industry with insightful news and analysis.

We understand that you are aware of and care about your own personal privacy interests, and we take that seriously, but we also want you to benefit from our online services. Lebhar-Friedman, Inc. sites are committed to bringing you information tailored to your individual needs and, at the same time, to protecting your privacy.

This Privacy Policy, which applies to all sites produced by LF and its affiliates whose websites are directly linked (the “Sites”), describes LF’s policies and practices regarding its collection and use of your personal data and sets forth your privacy rights. We recognize that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility, and so we will from time to time update this Privacy Policy as we undertake new personal data practices or adopt new privacy policies.

**HOW WE COLLECT AND USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

  1. Personal information you give to us: 
    1. Website Registration  
When you register on our websites, we collect information about you including your name, your employer’s name, your job title, your business type, your job function and your email address. We may also collect your work address, phone number, company size, and annual revenue. Registered users may edit their account information at any time to change or add personal information. 

We process your personal information to deliver customized content to you, invite you to events, and other benefits or opportunities associated with your registration. LF may also use this information to understand our user’s interests to better provide content and services to meet your needs.

    2. Live events and web conferences  
LF hosts several events throughout the year. These include in-person conferences like the SPECS Show, Industry Issues Summit, or ProDealer Industry Summit as well as live web conferences (collectively “events”). If you register for one of our events, we will store your registration information in our database and use it to provide you with information and services associated with the event. 

We keep a record of your participation in the events as an attendee or presenter. This information may be used to provide you with information about other events. It may also be used to help LF understand the attendees’ needs and interests to better tailor our products and services. 

Some of our events are sponsored. LF may provide an attendee list to sponsors, co-sponsors and exhibitors of our events.

    3. Content  
LF offers a great deal of content to our readers. In addition to producing original content, LF also links content produced by others. You will be leaving the LF websites when you click on these links. LF is not responsible or liable for content provided by these third party websites or personal information they may happen to gather from you. 

You may wish to subscribe to LF’s newsletters without registering on the website. For example, many readers sign up to receive the daily newsletter even though they don’t complete the full web registration. In order to sign up to receive any newsletters by email you will need to provide us with at least your email address. 

You may manage your subscriptions by subscribing or unsubscribing at any time. If you have any difficulties managing your email or other communication preferences with LF, please contact us at [data@lf1925.com](mailto:data@lf1925.com). 

LF uses Google Analytics and a CDP to track how often people gain access to or read our content. We use this information in the aggregate to understand what content our readers find useful or interesting, so we can produce the most valuable content to meet your needs and recommend similar content based on content preferences.The polls that we conduct are tracked through browser cookies, but the information is reported in aggregate only. Participation in polls is voluntary.

    4. Your correspondence with LF  
If you correspond with us by email, we may retain such correspondence and the information contained in it and use it to respond to your inquiry; to notify you of LF events, publications or other services; or to keep a record of your complaint, accommodation request, and the like. As always if you wish to have LF “erase” your personal information or otherwise refrain from communicating with you, please contact us at [data@lf1925.com](mailto:data@lf1925.com).
    5. Purposes for processing your data  
As explained above, LF processes your data to provide you with the goods or services you have requested or purchased from us, including web registration, events, newsletters, magazines and other content. We use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Sites, including to: 

• Provide you with content, products and services you request  
• Post your comments on our Sites as you request  
• Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you information about features and enhancements on or to our Sites  
• Personalize content and experiences on our Sites, including providing you with content recommendations based on your preferences  
• Send you newsletters, offers and promotion for our products and services, third party products and services, or special events by email or other medium  
• Provide you with advertising including advertising based on your activity on our Sites  
• Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites and their purchasing patterns

    6. Payment card information  
You may choose to purchase goods from LF using a payment card. Typically, payment card information is provided directly by users, via the LF websites, into the payment processing service to which LF subscribes. LF does not process or store the card information. Occasionally, users or customers ask LF employees to, on their behalf, enter payment information into the payment processing service to which LF uses. We strongly encourage you not to submit this information by email. When LF employees receive payment information from customers by email, fax, phone or mail, it is entered as instructed and then deleted or destroyed.
  2. Personal information we get from third parties 
    1. From time to time, LF receives personal information about individuals from thirds parties. This may happen if your employer signs you up for a newsletter, subscription, training or event attendance. This may also happen if LF sponsors an event that you have or will attend.
    2. We may supplement the information you provide us and the information we collect above with information from third parties or collected offline and add it to your account information. This information may include, but is not limited to your IP address, geographic information, browser and device type, demographic information, additional contact information, group affiliations, content preferences, occupational information, social media profiles, and education background.

**USE OF THE LF SITES**  
LF Sites collect certain information automatically and store it in log files. The information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of the Sites, including a history of the pages you view. We use this information to help us design our site to better suit our user’s needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website, analyze trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information that assists us in identifying visitor preferences. The LF Sites also use cookies and web beacons.

  * Cookies and web beacons  
Cookies are pieces of data that a Web site transfers to user’s hard drive for record keeping purposes. Web beacons are transparent pixel images that are used in collecting information about website usage, email response and tracking.The Sites use cookies and web beacons to provide enhanced functionality on the site and aggregate traffic data. These cookies may be delivered in a first-party or third-party context. LF may also use cookies and web beacons in association with emails delivered by LF. Our Sites also capture limited information about visits to our Site; we may use this information to analyze general traffic patterns and to perform routing system maintenance. You have many choices with regards to the management of cookies on your computer. All major browsers allow you to block or delete cookies from your system. To learn more about your ability to manage cookies and web beacons please consult the privacy features in your browser.The Sites also use third-party provided web analytics services. These analytics services use cookies or other tracking technologies to help us analyze how users interact with and use the Sites, compile reports on the Sites’ activity, and provide other services related to the Sites’ activity and usage. The technologies used by these analytics services may collect information such as your IP address, time of visit, whether you are a return visitor, and any referring website. The information generated by these analytics services will be transmitted to and stored by the third parties and will be subject to their privacy policies. We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies, how they may be used, or the information they may collect, and we are not responsible for the privacy policies of these third parties. Please visit the sites of these businesses to review their privacy policies. We may add or change the list of third party providers of analytics service from time to time and we encourage you to check this section for changes. The third-party companies that provide analytics services on our Sites are: 
    * DoubleClick for Publishers
    * Cheetah Digital
    * BlueConic

We may partner with third party advertising companies to better provide advertisements about our goods and services that may be of interest to you. We may also allow third-party ad serving companies and other unaffiliated advertisers to display advertisements on our site. These third-party advertisers and ad serving companies may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use the Sites. As part of their service, they may place a separate cookie on your computer, device, or browser, or utilize other data collection and tracking technologies, to collect information such as your IP address, browser type, the server your computer, device or browser is logged onto, the area code and zip code associated with your server, and whether you responded to a particular advertisement. They may collect information about your online activities over time, across different computers, devices, and browsers, and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide interest-based advertising or other targeted content.

We will not provide these online advertising partners or ad serving companies with access to your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other personally identifiable information, without your consent. They may, however, use persistent identifiers to anonymously track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond these Sites. While we restrict any attempts to re-identify this information, such third parties may, with sufficient data from other sources, be able to personally identify you, unknown to us. Third party advertisers may also already possess personally identifiable information about you, obtained from other sources, and may combine such information with information they collect about you when you use the Sites.

  * Do not track  
Your browser or device may include “Do Not Track” functionality. Because a “Do Not Track” compliance protocol has not yet been finalized, LF’s information collections and disclosure practices, and the choices that we provide to users, will continue to operate as described in this privacy policy, whether or not a Do Not Track signal is received.

**YOUR OPTIONS**  
You should have options about the collection, use and sharing of your information. Although you cannot opt-out of all data collection when you visit our Sites, you can limit the collection, use and sharing of your personally identifiable information. For information regarding your choices for interest-based advertising, please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/), consult with your social network’s preference tools, check your browser settings, and learn about your options to opt-out of mobile tracking.

Please note that opting-out of advertising networks services does not mean that you will not receive advertising while using our Sites, nor will it prevent the receipt of interest-based advertising from third parties that do not participate in these programs. It will, however, exclude you from interest-based advertising conducted through participating networks, as provided by their policies and choice mechanisms.

Most personally identifiable information is provided on a voluntary basis. You can enjoy many of LF’s services without giving us your personal data. If you do not want LF to collect such information, you should not submit it to the Sites. However, doing so will restrict your ability to access some content and use some of the functionality of the Sites.

You may always opt-out of receiving future e-mail marketing messages and newsletters from LF by clicking on the preference center or unsubscribe links contained within every email and newsletter, or by e-mailing us at [data@lf1925.com](mailto:data@lf1925.com) and indicate what you would like to opt-out of.

**WHEN AND HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WITH OTHERS**  
Information about your LF subscriptions and profiles are maintained in association with your user profile account. The personal information LF collects from you is stored in one or more databases hosted by third parties located in the United States. These third parties do not use or have access to your personal information for any purpose other than cloud storage and retrieval. On occasion, LF engages third parties to mail information to you, including items like magazines you many have subscribed to, or material from an event sponsor.

We do not otherwise reveal your personal data to third-parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorize it; (2) it’s in connection with LF hosted and co-sponsored events as described above; (3) the information is provided to comply with the law (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order), enforce and agreement we have with you, or to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees or others; (4) the information is provided to our agents, vendors or service providers who perform functions on our behalf; (5) to address emergencies or acts of God; or (6) to address disputes, claims, or to persons demonstrating legal authority to act on your behalf. We may also gather aggregated data about our users and Site visitors and disclose the results of such aggregated (but not personally identifiable) information to our partners, service providers, advertisers and/or other third parties for marketing or promotional purposes.

LF Sites uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to “like” or share information from the LF Sites through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.

**DATA SUBJECT RIGHTS**  
The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation and other countries’ privacy laws provide certain rights for data subjects.

This privacy policy is intended to provide you with information about what personal data LF collects about you and how it is used.

If you wish to confirm that LF if processing your personal data, or to have access to the personal data LF may have about you, please contact us at [data@lf1925.com](mailto:data@lf1925.com).

You may also request information about: the purpose of the processing; the categories of personal data concerned; who else outside LF might have received the data from LF; what the source of the information was (if you didn’t provide it directly to LF); and how long it will be stored. You have a right to correct the record of your personal data maintained by LF if it is inaccurate. You may request that LF erase that data or cease processing it, subject to certain exceptions. You may also request that LF cease using your data for direct marketing purposes. In many countries, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have concerns about how LF processes your personal data. When technically feasible, LF will, at your request, provide your personal data to you or transmit it directly to another controller.

The Sites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive information from children.

**SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION**  
To help protect the privacy of data and personally identifiable information you transmit through use of this site, we maintain physical, technical and administrative safeguards. We do update and test our security technology

**DATA STORAGE AND RETENTION**  
Your personal data is stored by LF on its servers and on the server of the cloud-based database management service LF engages, located in the United States.

**CHANGES AND UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY**  
By using this Site, you agree to the terms and conditions contained in this Privacy Policy and Conditions of Use and/or any other agreement that we might have with you. If you do not agree to any of these terms and conditions, you should not use this Site or any LF services. You agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Policy and Conditions of Use, or any other agreement we have with you, will be governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of New York. You also agree to arbitrate such disputes in New York, and to abide by any limitation on damages contained in any agreement we may have with you.

As our organization and services change from time to time, this Privacy Policy and Conditions of Use is expected to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the Privacy Policy and Conditions of Use at any time, for any reason, without notice to you, other than the posting of the amended Privacy Policy and Conditions of Use at this Site. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and terms and conditions and will e-mail LF users material changes thereto, but you should check our Site frequently to see the current Privacy Policy and Conditions of Use that is in effect and any changes that may have been made to it. The provisions contained herein supersede all previous notices or statements regarding our privacy practices and the terms and conditions that govern the use of this Site.

For EU Privacy Settings click here.

**QUESTIONS, CONCERNS OR COMPLAINTS**  
Please contact us at:  
Lebhar-Friedman  
150 West 30th Street  
New York, NY 10010  
212-756-5000
